Welcome back to Insurance Worlds. So in
today's video, I am going to introduce you to the best critical illness policy
offered by nine general insurance companies in ICICI. The
name of this policy is Critical Shield Plus. 92
critical illnesses are
covered in this policy. Let's see how a critical
illness policy works. Just
like taking a personal accident policy,
we can also take out
this critical illness policy at a very low premium. At the
time of an event, that is, after this policy, if
we are
diagnosed with a
critical illness,
we can claim a lump sum
amount. This is
a concept that we can get and take.
One of the benefits of these critical illness policies is that when we
say critical illness policy, the one that we are
most familiar with is cancer in nature, right?  The
number of people affected by cancer is very high. If we look at a particular point of view,
20 to 25 lakh
people are affected by cancer. Out of this, about
7 lakh people are
newly diagnosed with cancer every year.
Not only that, 60 percent of these people are affected by this cancer, but many of them are in an
incurable state. So,
we can understand from this data that a critical illness policy is very necessary.
Now, let
's examine the details of this policy one by one.
This policy covers 92 major
critical illnesses,
that is, 55 major critical
illnesses and 37 minor critical
illnesses.
This policy covers 92 fatal illnesses. In
this, the severity-based
pay out comes in this policy, that is, if the
illness falling in this category is major,
100  If the percentage is minor,
we
get 25 percent as a lump sum payout. In
this policy, critical illnesses are
classified into five categories: Cancer and
Blood Disorder, Heart and Blood Vessels,
Major Organs, Nervous System, Other Illness.
We
classify all the important critical illnesses into five categories. We can say that these five categories of
illnesses or these five buckets are
OK. In one
bucket, there will be major illnesses and there will
be minor illnesses. There is no waiting period for making a claim between these.
That is, if we have a major
illness and we have
a minor illness along with it, there is no waiting period for
us in this
policy. Okay, so the multi-
claim option is available to us in each coverage.
Not only can we get
major illness and minor illness from one bucket, that is, from a critical illness bucket,
we can get cover for  What
can be done is that they have designed five
critical illness buckets in this
policy. So
what are those
five critical illness buckets? Let's
discuss which illnesses are major and minor.
Optional coverage in this policy is that if
we want to
get a severity-based payout for 106 surgical procedures,
we have an additional add-on
feature, that is, if it is a major surgery, we get
100% amount and if it is a minor surgery, we
get 50% amount.
We have to add this feature additionally.
Then, for those who have not taken the optional coverage personal
accident policy before, by
selecting an add-on rider in this policy itself,
a lump sum amount will be paid in the event of accidental death or permanent total disability, partial disability.
If you want a feature that you
can add on, then if you exhaust the fund amount in
a bucket given by cancer, you
can select an option that will get you a restoration again.
Then, like in
other companies, there is no condition that the waiting period will open
after 90 days of taking the policy. In
this policy, if
we get a fatal disease, the
concept of a 30-day survival period is
not applicable. Okay, so the survival
period or the waiting period will open after 90 days of taking the policy.
So, the good thing is that two conditions are not included in this
policy. If you
look at the eligibility condition, the proposer must
be at least 18 years old to become a proposer. If you
look at the minimum entry age, the insured member can be from three
months to 65 years old on an
individual basis.  This policy
can be taken, which means that
this policy cannot be taken on a family floater basis. If we
look at the policy period, we can take this policy for one
year or two years, up to a maximum of
three years. The
premium we
get in this policy is very low. Okay, so just like
a personal accident policy, the
premium is very affordable for us. In
this critical illness
policy,
we have classified the critical illness policies into five buckets. The
first of them is called cancer and blood
disorders. Out of these,
four are classified as major diseases and one as minor diseases. If it is
major, it is 100% and if it is minor,
we get 25 percent. We
get a severity-based payout.
Similarly, there are four other buckets,
i.e. if it is heart and blood vessels, it is
classified as major diseases and minor diseases. So
as we said today, 55 major
Illnesses and
minor illnesses, we have this critical
illness together, and now we have 92
critical illnesses
classified in this policy.
Similarly, there are three other critical
illnesses, the critical illness bucket that affects major organs, as well as the critical
illness bucket that affects the nervous system, which has
major and minor
illnesses. Similarly, the last
bucket is
called other illnesses, in which we are listed about three major illnesses and about
five minor illnesses.
So, if we look at the maximum coverage that
we can take in this policy, it is from
5 lakhs
to 40 lakhs. Okay, when
we go for a high coverage,
we will have all the underrating. So, as
I said earlier, we
can opt for each of these buckets individually if we want, or
we can also select and opt for add-ons,
or all
five buckets together.  We
get this comprehensive plan together, which is
called the Critical Shield Plan. If we
choose it comprehensively,
we can utilize all the buckets of cancer, starting with the Nervous System, Other Organs, Heart and Blood Vessels.
This
policy can be taken on an individual basis. If we
take a comprehensive plan for those aged 21 to 55 years, if we
take a plan that includes all five buckets, the
respective premium for
coverage of Rs. 5 lakh to Rs. 40 lakh is
given in this chart.
We are told to take it on an individual basis. This policy is very affordable for those below the age of 45. So,
for example, if we
say on an individual basis, a 30-year-old person can
join this policy by paying a premium of Rs. 1758.
I said that this is a premium for a coverage that includes five comprehensive buckets. If we want,
we can join together for three years.
This premium does not include any other add-on riders.
So, although we
cannot take this policy as a family floater, we
can take this policy separately for husband, wife and children on an individual basis.
Then the big thing is that we will have underwriting.
Then, in the same way,
we need to disclose our existing illnesses. Not only the health insurance
critical illness policy, but
all health insurance is
taken by us to take all the insurance. So, if we
take this policy by hiding any existing illnesses,
or if we
have a symptom that is already cancerous, we cannot take this policy or if we do not have
a heart-
related
problem, we
cannot take this policy. So, if we are fresh and have no
more problems with our current illnesses, we can take this policy.  This
policy can be used in an event that can be held in a futuristic way by taking this one policy.
Okay, so that
we can get that one eligible claim amount. So,
we need to disclose the existing diseases and mention them correctly. To apply for each policy, we just need to pay
attention to that. So, to know more details about this one policy and to
purchase the policy, you
can call the number 701273178 shown on this screen
or
you can
contact us through WhatsApp message on the number 9809827383 which is the WhatsApp number.
I will provide you with
policies that are suitable for you. My
name is Shiva. I am a
health insurance advisor. So, to
watch more useful videos like this, don't
forget to subscribe to our Insurance Worlds channel.
Share it with your friends and families.
Thank you.